A Guide to the Papers of the Republic Mining & Manufacturing Company 1933-1946
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Republic Mining & Manufacturing Company 1933-1946
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11526
ca. 1,100 items (2 Hollinger boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the University of Virginia Library from Clover Hill Books, on March 12, 1999.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the 1933, and chiefly 1940-1946, business records of several bauxite mines located in and around Spottswood, Augusta County, Virginia, operated by the Republic Mining and Manufacturing Company, based in New York City. Apparently, these mines were solely a wartime enterprise when the bauxite was used to produce aluminum for the defense industry during World War II.
The contents include payroll books and ledger sheets, correspondence to the Baltimore & Ohio Railroad Company requesting permission to construct a loading chute on the siding at Spottswood, a blueprint drawing for the chute, a memorandum concerning the J.C. Hebble property near Asheville, Alabama, mining maps and reports, laboratory reports on the quality of the ore mined, reports of explosives used in mining, bills of lading, a log of holes bored on Charles T. Lightner's farm (1933), reports of outbound freight, and workmen's time books kept for the Allen and Lightner Mines.
Contents List
- Bills of Lading - Baltimore & Ohio Railroad Company 1942, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Bills of Lading - Norfolk & Western Railway Company 1942-46, 5 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1940 & 1941 (Box 1)
- Laboratory Reports 1941-1944 & 1946, 3 folders (Box 1-2)
  1941-1943
- Log of Holes Bored on Charles T. Lightner Farm 1933 July (Box 2)
- Payroll Sheets 1943-1944, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Records of Explosives Used 1942-1943 (Box 2)
- Reports of Outbound Freight 1940-1946, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Workmen's Time Books for the Allen Mine and Lightner Mine, Spottswood, Virginia 1942, 3 bound volumes (Box 2)
- Allen Mine, Spottswood, Virginia, drawn by W.C. Warren and Otis M. Clarke, Jr. (Oversize OS Tray #10)
  several laboratory reports attached
- Harris Mine, Spottswood, Virginia, drawn by Otis M. Clarke, Jr. 1942 December (Oversize OS Tray #10)
- Harris Mine, Spottswood, Virginia, with Notation of Test Holes n.d. (Oversize OS Tray #10)
- Lightner Mine, Spottswood, Virginia, drawn by W.C. Warren and Otis M. Clarke, Jr. 1942 November (Oversize OS Tray #10)
- Blueprint for the Drop Chute for Boxcar Loading at Spottswood, Virginia 1943 March 27 (Oversize OS Tray #10)